it's going on shopkeepers just school
here and today we're gonna give you a
gem spending guy if we're gonna spend
over $100 on gems then we're gonna spend
it all and we'll show you exactly how
we'd go and do that if you like chop
Titans videos where we give you spending
guides optimization guides I mean if you
want to progress like subscribe because
we're really enjoying this game and man
we have learned a lot we have been
collaborating closely with Zampa from
discord known in game as tellin sitting
at number nine currently on the leader
board and who e did we learn a lot by
chatting with them over the last 48
hours about shop Titans so we're gonna
share a little bit of the guidance that
they had given me around spending in
this game and some of the things that we
learned along the way one of the first
things that we need to talk about with
regard to gems is that the presence of
the market makes it so that you really
need to be thinking about what the gold
coin equivalent is of your gems a
general rule of thumb is that one gem is
worth about ten thousand gold coins and
that is because frequently you can find
things on the market that lets you
convert them in that way it's a lot
easier a lot easier to convert gems into
gold than it is to go the other way
around to convert gold back into gems
cuz you've got to try and find a buyer
in the market so the guidance that I
would recommend and that talen
recommended is that you try to find the
things to spend gems on that have a
really positive ratio to that gem to
gold value let me give you a few
examples expanding your shop has a
really phenomenal ratio here these two
thousand gems are really worth about
twenty million gold but we're gonna if
we were gonna have to do this at level
50 by using gold we would have had to
have spend a hundred million gold
so this is a really good pickup and
we're gonna be doing that in a moment
the other thing that we use gems to do
is to get early access to things that we
wouldn't have been able to get for a
really long time I'm like at least a
week or two away from level 50 at best
and so getting access to the larger shop
early is a really big deal it's a great
place to be spending your gems if you've
got gems to spend there so let's pick up
the gems let's start to do the spending
and we'll explain a little bit more why
it is that we're spending in each of
these things because we're gonna expand
our shop we're also by the way we're
gonna go in and we're gonna increase the
number of crafting slots we have even
though this doesn't have the most
amazing gem to gold ratio we'll talk
about why it's worth doing anyways and
we're gonna open up a bunch of chests so
let's start by going to the shop and
picking up a solid $100 worth of gems oh
yes here we go let's snag that now okay
purchase is in we have just snagged a
cool 18,000 gems whoo that's a lot of
gems that's a lot of gems so now we got
to go spend them in a way that makes
sense the first thing we want to do is
expand the shop now why is it that we
want to expand the shop expanding the
shop is a really big deal because it
makes it so that you can have more items
in your in your shop more furniture and
the furniture we're going to be hunting
for is more display racks more display
racks means we have more energy and if
we have more energy that means that when
we surcharge we get more energy from the
surcharging because surcharging gives
you a percentage of your missing energy
so the more energy you have the
percentage stays the same but the total
amount of energy you get per SAR charge
is going up so we're gonna expand the
shop 2,000 gems for another eight slots
initially
confirming it bada-boom nice little
expansion to the shop let's see what the
next expansion is gonna run us whoo
3,000 gems but look again at this ratio
right 3,000 gems would be about 30
million gold in the market and here it's
gonna run us you know 250 million gold
at level 60 if we wanted to expand our
shop in this way I mean this seems like
a pretty sweet pickup to me the question
is where do we do it let's go back
Center maybe we'll rock back Center 3000
gems and confirm ok so we've just
expanded the shop twice now there's a
couple other benefits that you get from
expanding your shop which are included
in the FAQ by the way if you haven't
seen where that FAQ is you go into
settings you hit FAQ and you hit game
play and this is gonna give you a lot of
information a lot of information about
the game things like how do I get more
customers to visit this is determined by
two things how big your shop is which is
a part of why we just expanded our shop
and how many items you currently have on
display empty racks don't count so get
more items on display was this helpful
it most certainly was we'll put that in
there as feedback so if we head on back
we've expanded our shop for that reason
we really want to have the extra space
so that we can put more structures in
which we'll do in just a moment and
let's just see how much the next
expansion is gonna be a solid four
thousand gems but look at what it will
cost us 500 million gold and level 75
which is really far away um I don't know
that we're gonna spend all our gems this
second as this that's a lot of gems to
spend all at once we will probably go
and spend that but there's a couple
other things we wanted to spend on that
we should go do now one of those things
is increasing the number of crafting
slots now why is it then we want to
increase the number of crafting slots as
you level up in the game I originally
thought that's the six crafting slots
that I had by virtue of buying the two
sort of starter packs there are really
really good value by the way totally
worth buying if you're you know spending
money in this game I thought that
originally six was just like more than I
knew what to do with but now that the
resource generation of our town has gone
up now that things that I'm crafting
take in upwards of like 35 minutes to
crank out at t6 gear and we're well on
our way to t7 we've got a few of those
that we can unlock as soon as we level
up our workers a little bit more we're
finding that we really could take
advantage of more crafting slots and so
even though now the gem to gold value is
not in our favor for making this
purchase it's actually a thing that is
worth doing because we're gonna use this
to turn around a whole heck of a lot of
value between now and level fifty when
we could have bought it anyway is far
more than probably the five million a
value so we're gonna unlock the seventh
slot with gems and that is a thousand
gems and we'll confirm it
bada-boom and let's see oh do I have to
max out on things I'm crafting in order
to do that again okay that's fine
we can do that here we go now 1500 gems
for our next slot we're gonna do this
again even though the ratio is not
amazing and will confirm it will jam out
something else doesn't matter what PS
don't don't do what I'm doing right now
with all these people just waiting oh my
gosh
it's so painful to watch them just
sitting there I I'm so well trained to
just go deal with that
so now 2,000 gems and this would have
cost us 25 million gold this is actually
starting to look like a little bit more
of a favorable configuration we're gonna
do this unlock as well for the 9th
crafting slot for the cool 2000 gems
bada-boom and the next slot is 2500 gems
we know we're gonna want to expand the
shop we really should do two more
expansions certainly at least one more
expansion so we're going to hold off on
doing the final gem purchases there just
yet just to make sure that we
get a little bit more accustomed to what
we've already just purchased here and
then decide what we think is more
important the extra spaces or the extra
crafting slot I'm pretty sure it's gonna
be the extra spaces so now that we've
made those purchases by the way the
other thing I want to show you before I
go and I Jam just a whole bunch of the
furniture that I want to put into my
shop there's another thing that we want
to do here that is actually gonna get us
some solid progression and believe it or
not that is gonna be opening up some
loot chests now I know that sounds a
little wacky we've got a bunch of chests
saved up here but these wood chests are
not so bad if we look at the odds sure
the chance of a research scroll or a
champion coin or ascension chart is low
however you are guaranteed one
additional loot item and you're
guaranteed that it is a rare loot item
when you use gems to do the unlock so
it's actually not such a bad idea to be
jamming out some of these wooden chests
so we're gonna do that today just a few
of them just to show what that's like
because the thing that we're really
hunting for is the research scrolls
we're really hunting for the ascension
scrolls the hero coins and quite frankly
you know look I don't particularly want
to be sending my folks to question zone
one I don't really want to do that so if
I can just go in incrementally and use
some gems to get the crafting materials
I need along with the Ascension charts
and the tokens and all those other
goodies it's actually not such a bad
situation and then you know of course
you do the boss everyday so we're gonna
go in and do some magic unlocking gear
and we'll confirm here we go you can see
it's got a gem on the end of that key
some chipped rune stones seed of powers
a consumable that I'm really looking
forward to using to pump up my heroes
later on in the game I'm saving those up
some mushrooms
oh-ho hello well hello there
legendary legendary plate gauntlets I
mean look I know it's just play
gauntlets okay but its legendary and
that's freaking sweet
and there's the research scrolls there's
the research scrolls and that is why
that is why geminus is not such a
terrible idea we're preventing ourselves
from having to go back into that first
questing zone and we're getting some of
the goodies that we really kind of need
right now let's open up a few more and
talk about what we get here and how we
feel about it repair kit probably better
later on tellin Zampa on discord was
advising me that you know these repair
kits could be worth upwards of a million
gold later on when you've got really
really decked out heroes with crazy
expensive gear with crazy enchantments
on it so we'll hang on to those epic
iron male we really don't care about
that all that much you could buy that on
the auction house for you know probably
ten thousand gold or something from
chipped rune stones is fine the seat of
power is fine and there's our rare the
ascension shards a solid pick up a solid
pick up happy with that
let's rip a couple more here we go boom
glow shroom thief's gloves we really I
don't know maybe we'll hang on to those
for leveling up a new hero a seat of
power and hey argon coins we'll take
those we've recently got argon up to the
second level of his skill which is
pretty sweet
I think it's 20% defense and attack will
rip a couple more of these
here we go the bow we really don't care
about seed of resistance is fine seed of
power is good the oven wood is great we
need these crafting materials and
bada-boom research scrolls marvelous
freaking marvelous will open up a few
more of these and we're gonna talk about
some of the places that we didn't spend
our gems that could be a pretty good
place to go and spend them later or not
let's see here about a boom six more
ascension shards nice Rock a couple more
magic unlocks here more glow shrooms a
chapter in stone the XP drink I
pinecones and ascension shards I mean
you're basically guaranteed that you're
gonna get champion coins ascension cart
shards or research squirrels all of
those are things that we are happy to
snag right now really happy to snag hey
argon coins solid glow shrooms a repair
kit the power booster research scrolls
we need so many of those so you know
we're gonna be using things like the
glow shrooms to get more research
scrolls so this is going really quite
well as far as I'm concerned a couple
more of these XP drink seed of
resistance stamina drink chips rune
stones and yammy coins solid we'll take
ya me where is it Laurel haha that was a
terrible joke alright one last one here
we can chip rune stones elven wood the
phoenix feather to heal everybody power
boosters which we haven't started using
yet we're saving those and more research
squirrels really solid feel really good
about that all around really do need
those research squirrels pretty
desperately this seems like a fine way
to go about doing this I suspect it if
you were dreaming higher tier chests you
might be getting better stuff more rare
stuff which is entirely possible we can
use some of the keys we have now just to
play around with that we've got in this
chest the phoenix feather the precious
gems the web's the chip Bruin stones and
no guaranteed rare fine but not
incredible the next level chest we open
and exp drink living route the XP quest
booster stamina drink and that's it
right no guaranteed rare continuing up
the chain here about a boom whoo
superior rap Toria hmm okay that's
interesting a super lute bugle that's a
pretty sweet looking Bureau I'm not
gonna lie the XP booster a cedar oh two
seats of resistance that's nice I mean
still again no coins no research shards
no ascensions and this would be a
hundred and fifty gems right I coulda
had three of the other chests
for one of these let's do this another
time
bada-boom Braun's fangs whoo now that
we're probably gonna lock to hold on to
a flawed with flawed rune stones are
good the chips are in stones are fine
and that's it and that's it one last
chest we're gonna then we're gonna
actually talk about the stuff we didn't
spend gems on here we go
dropping this in star metal 30 of it
superior fishmonger okay sure
super power booster so that increases
your quest party's power a phoenix
feather and that's it so you can see you
know 300 gems over here you could do six
of these earlier chests and you get
those guaranteed rares it's not so bad
the way you'd get your wooden chests by
the way this is how I did it is to put a
request in to the auction house for a
wooden chest at a price that you like I
did a thousand gold so each of those
chests cost me a thousand gold it was
like there's nothing you know
now let's talk about where we didn't
spend our gems because this I think is
kind of interesting one thing we could
go do is get the extra hero slot right
now and well that is interesting
while that is interesting the problem
here is that we're gonna hit level 44
pretty soon anyways at that point we can
spend gold and you know look this is
about seventeen and a half million gold
worth of gems so I'm better off waiting
at this point I'm better off waiting
until we get to level 44 to actually go
and spend this it's possible this might
have been worth of gems if I had done it
a long time ago but since I didn't it's
probably not worth it the other thing we
could do by the way is you could gem out
the higher tier of Heroes it cost like a
thousand gems to get the highest tier of
hero and that is another example where
gosh a thousand gems is worth ten
million gold so I'm better off probably
waiting until level 45 and 48 and 50 to
get
highest here of hero rather than
spending the gems on that because it's
gold and efficient so now let's go in
now let's go in holy moly we've got a
lot going on here and do some of the
things that we really need to do since
we've got a much bigger shop now which
is really quite excellent so one of the
first things we really want to do is get
more furniture in and the furniture
we're looking to get in is these racks
these are tremendously important
elevating our energy so let's start with
some shelves
since we are lower on shelves than other
things right now and I'm not gonna
locate these correctly now I'm just
gonna place them all so we'll get in
some shelves will spend the ten thousand
gold no problemo bada boom and you can
see our energy went up we're now up to
392 I'll do that again you can watch a
little more closely also by the way
let's see can we see our inventory space
our storage space it's not display all
right I'm gonna sell something real
quick we'll just do this slightly and
efficiently so we're at two hundred and
seventy three storage space right now
and if I build another structure will
put a little more furniture in let's jam
some more shelves we'll rotate it for
now drop it in over here fifteen
thousand gold no problem now let's see
how much we're up to two hundred and
seventy seven so we're getting inventory
space even though it doesn't say oh this
gives you inventory space and energy our
energies going up our inventory space is
going up and this is helping
tremendously tremendously especially
because we're gonna jam some upgrades on
these relatively quickly to give us a
whole bunch of more energy right away
which is really good now if we go edit
and furniture can we put in more shells
oh we can fascinating I thought that was
a cap on that but whatever okay so we'll
just drop these in and they're you know
you want to have at least I'm told three
of each display type but after that it's
sort of discretionary what you want to
do with that will spend the 15000 gold
bada-boom done our energies going up our
storage space is going up which is
amazing amazing let's see here Oh
interesting oh I see where the max
capacity is it's in the upper-left how
did I miss that before geez we're up to
281 solid
furniture put in a table the reason
we're doing these relatively evenly
right now is that oh and we're gonna
lock down that new weapon we got earlier
lock that down yeah that's a sweet
freakin weapon I bet you we could equip
that to somebody by the way I bet you we
could equip that to somebody a couple
more purchases will make initially here
boom mannequin drop it in confirm 15,000
gold about a boom now if we wanted to
add more of these which would probably
will that's 20,000 gold like that
doesn't seem like that big of an expense
to me doesn't seem like that became
expensive me will probably drop a couple
more of these in to increase our maximum
capacity for resources that seems like
it will could be pretty bad valuable to
us and otherwise we're in a pretty good
position here we're in pretty good
position here so my friends I hope that
this gem spending guide has been helpful
I'll summarize it now right one gem is
worth about ten thousand gold that
changes based on market dynamics you
want to gem on things that get them to
you way earlier than you would have got
them otherwise and also have a really
positive ratio of gold you could have
bought with gems to the actual gold cost
to buy it with gold assuming it even has
that option available to you so that
means practically speaking that things
like expanding your store is a really
big deal goes a very long way things
like increasing your crafting slots
which you will use to generate more
money goes a really long way and it's
really not so bad at all to gem some
wooden chests you don't then have to
go into zone 1 to do as much questing of
course he goes to kill the boss and you
can get those chests in the auction
house for like thousand gold a pop
pretty easy so we picked up a whole
bunch of research and ascension charts
and coins doing that not so bad at 50
gems a pop PS if you want to check out
talons twitch where he streams shop
Titans I'll put a link in the
description you should definitely check
that out
I know I learned a thing or two my
friends I hope that you found this gem
spending guide helpful the next time you
see my shop it's probably gonna look a
whole heck of a lot different because
we're gonna spend the remaining nine
thousand two hundred or so gems and
we've got a lot of rearranging to do a
lot of rearranging to do to make this
shop look a little bit more presentable
until next time my friends you have fun
getting sweet sweet deals